Guide to the New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences Dept. of Plant Pathology records, 1913-1983.
New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences Dept. of Plant Pathology records,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences Dept. of Plant Pathology records, 1913-1983.
21-29-544
New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences Dept. of Plant Pathology.
14.9 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Photographs, Research Materials, Scrapbooks
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes class rosters and grade books; student grade reports; lists of course registrations and fees; reports and results of experiments, etc.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes class rosters and grade books; student grade reports; lists of course registrations and fees; reports and results of experiments, mostly potato and small grain experiments, such as for control of disease; Fellowship Reports of the New York Florists' Club, the Nassau County Farm Bureau, and the American Rose Society; U.S. Department of Agriculture correspondence, mostly regarding agricultural agreements with South American countries; correspondence of agricultural colleges and agricultural experiment stations, including the Cornell College of Agriculture and Life Sciences and the New York State Agricultural Experiment Station; project proposals and budget estimates; agenda for meetings; photographs and scrapbook; and other records of the Cornell Department of Plant Pathology.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences.; American Rose Society.; Cornell University--Curricula.; Cornell University--Students.; Nassau County Farm Bureau.; New York Florists' Club.; New York State Agricultural Experiment Station.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences.; United States.Dept. of Agriculture.
Subjects:
Plant diseases.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
  - Potato Dusting Experiment Reports by Phares Decker, 1920-1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Potato Dusting/Potato Diseases Reports, 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Seed Treatments, 1920s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Potato Projects, 1929-1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Potato Seed Treatment Experiments, 1934-1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Potato Yellow Dwarf-James Rebstock, 1939-1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Hop Weather Record, 1913-1915 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Professor Blodgett's Files, 1933-1951 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Potato Spraying Results-Summary Tables (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hevea Taxonomy (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Plant and Fungi Specimens Collected by Karl Bulter, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Seed, Seedling and Packing Instructions, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Agreements-Karl Butler, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - New York Florist's Club Fellowship-Bickerton's Weekly Reports on the Carnation Fellowship, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - New York Florist's Club Fellowship-Bickerton's Weekly Reports on the Diseases of Carnations, 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Staten Island Grower's Association-Fellowship Notes by A.A. Foster, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - American Silver Producers' Research Project, 1931-1939 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Nassau County Farm Bureau Fellowships, 1936-1941 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Fungicidal Properties of Silver-Weekly Reports by L.W. Nielson, 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - American Rose Society Fellowship, 1929-1931 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Bayer Fellowship in Plant Pathology-Fellow-J.S. Wiant, 1924-1927 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Flag-Smut Map, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Small Grains Technical Committee and Regional Projects, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Small Grains Technical Committee-Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Cornell Projects, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Regional Research Project Meeting, January 1957 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Regional Research Project Meeting, January 1958 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Small Grains Technical Committee, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - New York Contributing Projects-Breeding of Small Grains, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Wheat-Articles, 1925-1932 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Materials Regarding the PhD Thesis of C. V. Kightlinger on Dusting as Cereal Rust Prevention, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Project Reports on Project 120, Potato "Z" Disease, 1935-1952 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Reports on Potato Spraying Experiments of Charles M. Wright and others, 1942-1949 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Reports on Potato Experiments, 1918-1947 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Reports on Potato Disease Experiments of F. M. Blodgett and Minutes of New York Potato Conference, 1935-1939 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Reports on Potato Experiments and Reports to the Central-Western New York Potato Committee, 1936-1942 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Regarding Spraying, 1943-1946 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Studies on Potato Leaves including Pressed Leaf Samples, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Course Grade Booklets; Graduate Student Records, 1913-1918; 1928-1945 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Scapbook, 1919-1962 (Box 4)
  - Comprehensive Review Material-Dept. of Plant Pathology, NYSAES, October 1977 (Box 4)
  - Comprehensive Review Material-Dept. of Plant Pathology, NYSAES, March 1983 (Box 4)
  - Department Annual Reports (Box 5)
  - Project Reports (Box 6)
  - Project Reports (Box 7)
  - Project Index, Project Reports - Project 1-21, 1930 (Box 8)
  - Historical, Miscellany, Correspondence, 1917-1918, 1948-1952 (Box 9)
  - Graduate Students (Box 10)
  - Project Reports - Project 22-59, 1930 (Box 11)
  - Project Reports - Project 60-159, 1930 (Box 12)
  - Project Reports - Project 160-225, 1930 (Box 13)
  - Project Reports - Project 228-, 1930 (Box 14)
  - Industrial Fellowship Memo of Understanding, Department Annual Reports, Budget, 1909-1955, 1961-1973, 1905-1949 (Box 15)
  - Budget, 1905-1949 (Box 16)
- Photographs
  - Unidentified photos (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - E.C.Stakman-St. Paul (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - B.T. Dickson (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Robert Flint (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Leslie Stephan? (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - John Caird (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Nevil Vincent Sidgwick (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - John Stuart Mill (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Plant Pathology Faculty and Photo with Whetzels, Agnes McAllister, Jensens, Galloway and others (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Summer Meeting of Phytopathologists, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Edward Caird (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - James Martineau (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - M.F. Barrus (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Photos of Buller, Arthur, Whetzels, Barrus and others (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Group of Men-identified (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Blodgett and the Whetzel Family (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Herbert Whetzel (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Plant Pathologists at the Conference of the War Emergency Board and photo of unidentified plant pathologists, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Beverly Thomas Galloway and photo of a medallion of Galloway (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Plant Pathology Students? (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Pathologists at War Conference and group visiting the California Redwoods, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Cereal Disease Conference, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Ind. Beta, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Plant Pathology Staff and Students, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Botanical and Physiology Meeting, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 25)